<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Flora Wenyao Jiang</title>
    <link>https://ffflora.cat/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Flora Wenyao Jiang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 19:29:26 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ffflora.cat/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Machine Learning Specialty Prep List</title>
      <link>https://ffflora.cat/posts/2021/01/aws-machine-learning-specialty-prep-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 19:29:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ffflora.cat/posts/2021/01/aws-machine-learning-specialty-prep-list/</guid>
      <description>Here are some resources I collected for better preparing the AWS Machine Learning Specialty Exam.
Practical experience aws/amazon-sagemaker-examples
Object Detection with Amazon Sagemaker
AWS Training offers digital courses on machine learning (ML).   Data Analytics Fundamentals
  Exam Readiness: AWS Certified Machine Learning - Specialty
  Deep Learning on AWS
  Elements of Data Science
  Math for Machine Learning
  Linear and Logistic Regression</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Machine Learning Exam Readiness with Sample Questions</title>
      <link>https://ffflora.cat/posts/2021/01/aws-machine-learning-exam-readiness-with-sample-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:20:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ffflora.cat/posts/2021/01/aws-machine-learning-exam-readiness-with-sample-questions/</guid>
      <description>These are my study notes directly from AWS Training cource - AWS Machine Learning Exam Readiness.
Domain 1: Data Engineering Create Data Repo for Machine Learning Identify and implement a data ingestion solution To use the data for ML, you need to ingest it into a service like Amazon S3
Batch and stream processing are two kinds of data ingestion.
Batch processing Batch processing periodically collects and groups source data.With batch processing, the ingestion layer periodically collects and groups source data and sends it to a destination like Amazon S3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Data Analytics Fundamental with AWS Solutions</title>
      <link>https://ffflora.cat/posts/2021/01/intro-to-data-analytics-fundamental-with-aws-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:19:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ffflora.cat/posts/2021/01/intro-to-data-analytics-fundamental-with-aws-solutions/</guid>
      <description>The challenges identified in many data analysis solutions can be summarized by five key challenges: volume, velocity, variety, veracity, and value.
Volume - Data Storage  Structured(10%) data is organized and stored in the form of values that are grouped into rows and columns of a table. Semistructured(10%) data is often stored in a series of key-value pairs that are grouped into elements within a file. Unstructured(80%) data is not structured in a consistent way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Auto Completion in GCP</title>
      <link>https://ffflora.cat/posts/2019/08/how-to-use-auto-completion-in-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 21:30:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ffflora.cat/posts/2019/08/how-to-use-auto-completion-in-gcp/</guid>
      <description>Auto-completion gcloud interactive has auto prompting for commands and flags, and displays inline help snippets in the lower section as the command is typed.
Static information, like command and sub-command names, and flag names and enumerated flag values, are auto-completed using dropdown menus.
Install the beta components:
gcloud components install beta Enter the gcloud interactive mode:
gcloud beta interactive When using the interactive mode, click on the Tab key to complete file path and resource arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>